{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The reference fuels for knock rating of spark ignition engines would include", "opta": "iso-octane and alpha-methyl naphthalene", "optb": "normal octane and aniline", "optc": "iso-octane and normal hexane", "optd": "normal heptane and iso-octane", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The diesel engines are also known as __________ engines.", "opta": "compression ignition", "optb": "spark ignition", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a four stroke cycle, the minimum temperature inside the engine cylinder occurs at the", "opta": "beginning of suction stroke", "optb": "end of suction stroke", "optc": "beginning of exhaust stroke", "optd": "end of exhaust stroke", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In hit and miss governing, the fuel supply is cut-off completely during one or more number of cycles.", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The thermal efficiency of a standard Otto cycle for a compression ratio of 5.5 will be", "opta": "25%", "optb": "50%", "optc": "70%", "optd": "100%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ratio of the volume of charge admitted at N.T.P. to the swept volume of the piston is called", "opta": "mechanical efficiency", "optb": "overall efficiency", "optc": "volumetric efficiency", "optd": "relative efficiency", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The exhaust valve in a four stroke cycle petrol engine", "opta": "opens at 50\u00b0 before bottom dead centre and closes at 15\u00b0 after top dead centre", "optb": "opens at bottom dead centre and closes at top dead centre", "optc": "opens at 50\u00b0 after bottom dead centre and closes at 15\u00b0 before top dead centre", "optd": "may open and close anywhere", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Nuclear reactors are used", "opta": "to produce heat for thermoelectric power", "optb": "to produce fissionable material", "optc": "to propel ships, submarines, aircrafts", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A moderator generally used in nuclear power plants is", "opta": "graphite", "optb": "heavy water", "optc": "concrete", "optd": "graphite and concrete", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The predominent isotope of the naturally occuring element is", "opta": "U235", "optb": "U238", "optc": "Pu233", "optd": "Pu239", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The brake power of a diesel engine, keeping other parameters constant, can be increased by", "opta": "decreasing the density of intake air", "optb": "increasing the temperature of intake air", "optc": "increasing the pressure of intake air", "optd": "decreasing the pressure of intake air", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In diesel engines, the fuel is injected in the form of very fine spray, into the engine cylinder, which gets ignited due to high temperature of the compressed air.", "opta": "Agree", "optb": "Disagree", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pre-ignition is caused by the spontantaneous combustion of the mixture before the end of the compression stroke, and is due to", "opta": "cylinder walls being too hot", "optb": "overheated spark plug points", "optc": "red hot carbon deposits on cylinder walls", "optd": "any one of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The expansion of fuel in a four stroke cycle diesel engine", "opta": "starts at 15\u00b0 before top dead centre and ends at 30\u00b0 after top dead centre", "optb": "starts at top dead centre and ends at 30\u00b0 after top dead centre", "optc": "starts at 15\u00b0 after top dead centre and ends at 30\u00b0 before bottom dead centre", "optd": "may start and end anywhere", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The object of supercharging the engine is", "opta": "to reduce mass ofthe engine per brake power", "optb": "to reduce space occupied by the engine", "optc": "to increase the power output of an engine when greater power is required", "optd": "all ofthe above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In open combustion chamber in diesel engines, the shape and layout of the piston crown, the inlet port and the valve produce the turbulent effect of fuel mixture.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a four stroke cycle petrol engine, the charge is ignited at", "opta": "30\u00b0 before top dead centre", "optb": "30\u00b0 after top dead centre", "optc": "30\u00b0 before bottom dead centre", "optd": "30\u00b0 after bottom dead centre", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A moderator, in nuclear power plants, is a medium introduced into the fuel mass in order to", "opta": "slow down the speed of fast moving neutrons", "optb": "control the reaction", "optc": "reduce the temperature", "optd": "extract heat from nuclear reaction", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Where reactor operation is designed with fast neutrons such as in reactors using highly enriched fuel, the moderator used is", "opta": "heavy water", "optb": "graphite", "optc": "carbon dioxide", "optd": "no moderator is needed", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a diesel engine, the duration between the time of injection and ignition, is known as", "opta": "pre-ignition period", "optb": "delay period", "optc": "period of ignition", "optd": "burning period", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The detonating tendency in petrol engines increases with increase of compression ratio.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Each fission of U235 produces on the average __________ fast neutrons as a product of reaction.", "opta": "2.46", "optb": "24.6", "optc": "246", "optd": "2460", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Reactors for propulsion applications are designed for", "opta": "any form of uranium", "optb": "natura uranium", "optc": "enriched uranium", "optd": "plutonium", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The primary fuel used in nuclear power plants is", "opta": "U235", "optb": "U238", "optc": "Pu239", "optd": "Pu233", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In petrol engine, using a fixed octane rating fuel and fixed compression ratio, supercharging will __________ the knocking tendency.", "opta": "not effect", "optb": "decrease", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ordinary water is sometimes used as moderator when enriched uranium is used as a fuel in nuclear power plants.", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The compensating jet in a carburettor supplies almost constant amount of petrol at all speeds because the", "opta": "jet area is automatically varied depending on the suction", "optb": "the flow from the main jet is diverted to the compensating jet with increase in speed", "optc": "the diameter of the jet is constant and the discharge coefficient is invariant", "optd": "flow is produced due to the static head in the float chamber", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The effective inhibitor of pre-ignition is", "opta": "alcohol", "optb": "water", "optc": "lead", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The purpose of testing an internal combustion engine is", "opta": "to determine the information, which can not be obtained by calculations", "optb": "to conform the data used in design, the validity of which may be doubtful", "optc": "to satisfy the customer regarding the performance of the engine", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The thermal efficiency of diesel engines is about", "opta": "15%", "optb": "30%", "optc": "50%", "optd": "70%", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A diesel engine has", "opta": "one valve", "optb": "two valves", "optc": "three valves", "optd": "four valves", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The self ignition temperature of petrol is __________ as compared to diesel oil.", "opta": "same", "optb": "lower", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The pressure inside the cylinder is __________ the atmospheric pressure during the exhaust stroke.", "opta": "equal to", "optb": "below", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The increase of cooling water temperature in petrol engine will __________ the knocking tendency.", "opta": "not effect", "optb": "decrease", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A carburettor is used to supply", "opta": "petrol, air and lubricating oil", "optb": "air and diesel", "optc": "petrol and lubricating oil", "optd": "petrol and air", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "U233 is produced", "opta": "artificially", "optb": "as basic raw material", "optc": "when thorium is irradiated by neutrons", "optd": "by fission of U238", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The pressure at the end of compression, in diesel engines, is approximately", "opta": "10 bar", "optb": "20 bar", "optc": "25 bar", "optd": "35 bar", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The detonation is also called knocking or pinking.", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The pre-ignition occurs before the spark is produced whereas detonation develops after the introduction of spark.", "opta": "Agree", "optb": "Disagree", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The energy released during the fission of one atom of Uranium - 235 in million electron volts is about", "opta": "100", "optb": "200", "optc": "300", "optd": "400", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Morse test can be conducted for", "opta": "petrol engines", "optb": "diesel engines", "optc": "multi-cylinder engines", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The basic requirement of a good combustion chamber is", "opta": "minimum turbulence", "optb": "low compression ratio", "optc": "high thermal efficiency and power output", "optd": "low volumetric efficiency", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a four stroke cycle petrol engine, the charge is compressed when both the valves (i.e. inlet valve and exit valve) are closed,", "opta": "Agree", "optb": "Disagree", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The thermal efficiency of diesel engines on weak mixtures is", "opta": "unaffected", "optb": "lower", "optc": "higher", "optd": "dependent on other factors", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The injection pressure in a diesel engine is about", "opta": "10 bar", "optb": "100 bar", "optc": "150 bar", "optd": "500 bar", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "High speed compression engines operate on", "opta": "Otto cycle", "optb": "Diesel cycle", "optc": "Dual-combustion cycle", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a four stroke cycle petrol engine, the inlet valve", "opta": "opens at top dead centre and closes at bottom dead centre", "optb": "opens at 20\u00b0 before top dead centre and closes at 40\u00b0 after bottom dead centre", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The nuclear power station at Tarapur has the reactor of the __________ type.", "opta": "pressurized water", "optb": "boiling water", "optc": "gas cooled", "optd": "liquid metal cooled", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In nuclear power plants, due to reflector, less fuel is needed to generate sufficient neutrons to sustain a chain reaction.", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The secondary fuel used in nuclear power plants is", "opta": "U233 and Pu239", "optb": "U235 and Th232", "optc": "U235 and Pu238", "optd": "U233 and Pu238", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}